hello my name is green and welcome back
to another episode of hermitcraft today
is actually really really special
because
this is episode 100 of hermitcraft the
longest series that i've ever created in
minecraft on this channel this season
has been going on for over a year nearly
two years i can remember this time last
year it was the civil war so what i
thought we would do for the start of
this episode
is actually go over our journey so far
i'm sure there'll be people that
remember every single little thing that
we've done
and there'll be some that maybe came and
went and maybe lost the thread so what
we're going to do is sort of review and
travel
back in time to where we started which
is here and we're going to go through
our journey on hermitcraft and hopefully
go full circle
so where we started was
actually right here and when we got here
it was an empty ocean of course now it's
full of stuff
but our humble beginnings started here
in the shipwreck
that i encompassed in a bottle it's
obviously been encroached now
but here we are and there's actually
still stuff here i occasionally come
here when i'm in real desperate need of
oh i'm gonna take that and you know as
far as starter bases go i think this was
actually pretty good one of the things i
did i have in here was my to-do list my
greens hermitcraft bucket list
i don't know where all the signs have
gone
but most of them were actually fulfilled
during the course of this series and it
kind of feels good and it feels like
such a long time ago that i put this
list together but if we head down into
here this is sort of i ran out of space
so i made more
more here and oh my goodness
and over here i had some chicken farms i
had cow farm they're all gone now but
one of the big things that we did at
this stage
was we made squidward's house which
actually has my conduit in
and it got bumbo-fied pretty quickly now
the squidward house was on its own for a
little while and then scar came along
and made spongebob's pineapple under the
sea and
not a day goes by where someone doesn't
mention that patrick's house is missing
and it needs to be built and i've not
been ignoring them i've been waiting i
have been waiting until episode 100 what
we're gonna do is we're going to build
patrick's house right here right now and
we're going to complete the trio
as a symbol of the great achievement
episode 100. so
let's let's get this finally out of the
way and then the choir can sing and we
can rejoice
and everyone can stop leaving comments
about it
i don't know why people became so
obsessed with this and every now and
again it's still brought up in the
comments but
i thought i'd finally get this thing
finished and it's kind of got to be in
the right order right the patrick's
house then squidwards then spongebob's
house at the end and it's pretty simple
it's just a terracotta blob on the
ground and actually speed time lapsing
underneath water looks pretty cool
anyway i finally got this thing out of
the way please i beg you just just stop
with the comments now
and
it is
finished we have done
patrick's house in minecraft and we have
completed the trilogy and that's where
we're going to leave that part of the
story i don't really know what impact
this has
but it's something that people have been
asking for such a long time now actually
it's quite a good point it's it's when
you're up here you can barely see
patrick's house so one of the things
that we're going to need to fill it up
with is some sea pickles and actually
leads us to the next part of our story
because very early on in the series we
built our very first shop which was the
giant pickle jar and you know for the
start of the season this is pretty
resource intensive it had a
lot of glass a lot of water and all of
this yeah i spent a lot of time in the
early days and all of the all of the
pickle puns i totally forgot about these
this water could be a little cumbersome
yep you know i haven't filled this up
and no one's either complained yeah
there's actually no pickles left i'm
just gonna steal these they're on the
floor
and after the pickle shop
we went and made immediately another
shop which was just a place for me to
sell stuff
it was my cart
it was green's you lazy sod traveling
market buy grindy blocks at a cost why
is there an impulse head here
and blood
it's redstone but why is there
how long has this been here
there's absolutely nothing here there's
still uh um an unknown head on this one
and oh my goodness you remember this
wait
what the heck why is there a floating
green head there how long has that been
there this is where we sold guinea pig
green services where i could test other
people's builds or mini-games or
whatever
man that was a really long time ago
we'll we'll test anything for six
diamonds
hello
oh
maybe this shop wasn't such a good idea
why did i put myself in a cage
dear old dude
someone's gonna hire me eventually right
right
right guys
someone's gonna do it okay something
something really weird is going on
because there's a lot of hermit's heads
with a lot of
decorative
figurative
maybe literal blood
no there's a there's a javen head no
wait are these everyone that's this must
be everyone that's died so far
no there's there's etho and
just more steve heads well that's super
worrying
don't know when that started
either way after we built the cart we
actually made some pretty decent
progress on our base and my base is
actually one of the things that i'm most
proud of from this season it is enormous
especially as i built this so early on
in the series without the use of the
concrete machine at all i had to mine
and
grind each one of these blocks out
individually it is a enormous build
enormous and it went up layer by layer
by layer it goes all the way underwater
and it has this giant ring around it as
well for decoration i think out of all
the builds on hermitcraft this is one of
my absolute favorites it's just i don't
know it's just iconic but early on in
the season it was just this little bit
here and it went up layer by layer and
even though i didn't get all of the
insides perhaps decorated very much at
all
it's still a really really cool build to
fly through
and it goes all the way up to build
height this is literally as tall as it
could get
one of the things that we made soon
after we started the base was architect
mail do you remember this there's an
actual tube system linking mine and
mumbo's bases and a beacon changes color
if you send a message but we stopped
using it
yeah probably because no one checks
their mail anymore
oh man this is so awesome
after mumbo and i set up architect mail
that lovely little pipe that runs
through the ocean there we then went
ahead and made poultry man but soon
after that
we created the mumbo mustache remover
machine
one of the most sophisticated pieces of
technology that exists on the server it
hasn't been reset actually in a long
time and it hasn't actually been used in
a long time either
but man this this brings back memories
as well it's like a giant mumbotron
machine
and
oh yeah okay song
oh
it may have only been for one episode
but iskall mumbo and i we played golf
for a full hour and it was absolutely
wonderful cub has made one of the most
insane mini games that has ever been
made on this server and he made this
before the mini game district was even a
thing i bet loads of people can't wait
to get their hands on the mini golf mini
game once the map is ready to be
downloaded i remember when mumbo iskal
and i were playing and i was just
pretending to be a commentator i was
like and here's the sweden shorts it's
uh making a shot
we were pretty bad at it pretty soon
after that the green head hunt began
where i put loads of green heads all
over the map and i want to remind you at
that stage in the series there was no
sahara all of this was nothing this area
was undeveloped for ages i wonder if
there's actually any green heads that we
can find sometimes they pop up every now
and again i haven't seen any in a while
though but i think even after a year not
every single one has been located and
then after the green head hunt
of course
the biggest event of the entire season
took place
hermitcraft civil war
[Music]
this is turning out to be quite the tour
there's all sorts of buildings that have
their own story that have absolutely
nothing to do with me like all the
different shops scar made this guy also
made this there's a mumbo's filming shop
there's
concorp and all of their endeavors i
won't be able to give a full commentary
on absolutely everything like the hrn
has its own story this entire map is
chock-full of everything that's been
going on on a minecraft world for the
last nearly two years and it tells the
story just by looking around and nothing
says that better than the civil war and
it's about a year ago to the day
that that took place i remember many
many late nights
grinding out this base that everyone
looks everyone says it looks like a
brita filter a water filter of some kind
and i've got to say i kind of agree
kind of agree
uh but after that comparison
yeah i think it actually looks like a
pretty cool base and again so much
concrete so many things involved in this
and we had a doorbell with a witch on it
i think the
your mic is muted
what
and a gertrude actually got destroyed in
the great entity purge so there was a
point in the map where we updated
versions and
literally everything got deleted and
gertrude
[Music]
gertrude's one of them
you are a kind soul join the g team oh
man the g team there was an invoker that
would either kill you or not depending
on a random chance
there's all the drones around and then
here we have
team star
team star and i think there's still
do you remember this
all of these guys
they need a little nudge i think i did
it i think
uh
off they go
oh no
what the heck and it's one of the few
times that we got absolutely everyone on
the server involved in the same event in
the same recording and trust me that's
not easy to do but after that it left me
absolutely broke i didn't have a single
diamond to my name
and
that's when we started to get into the
business industry
but for that i really needed someone
else on the team except me and mumbo we
needed a third person now it's amazing
to think that
iskall wasn't part of the architects
until after the civil war but yeah after
the civil war i i got him a handwritten
letter sent all the way to sweden
just to invite him to mumbo and eyes
little club
and it was pretty cool
[Music]
after that two things happened and they
happen to be right next to each other
the first thing that i did was i created
sherlock green's
tutti i can't remember what i called it
actually uh 2 2 1 g baker street
that's wonderful and then i think
there's even a door i hope no one's
oh my goodness i spent ages trying to
get that jingle right
boom
huh
that's meant to work
there we go there we go
boom
oh man do you remember this oh that's a
really cool ceiling i forgot about that
man sherlock green's place was super
cool wait i swear i had a there we go
yeah i had a little secret bunker which
the paintings have mysteriously changed
i i've got a little secret room in here
i've totally forgotten about this would
be an excellent place to hide things
because i don't think anyone's going to
come back here
well while sherlock green was starting
to figure out what the jangler was all
about which actually just turned out to
be
a terrible copy of the jingler
we started sahara and we started with
the building over here at the back with
all the redstone stuff and when we
started it was actually it was actually
pretty small
and then it just got out of control
this is one of the most impressive
redstone contraptions for the simplest
task you would think that making a shop
with redstone like this would be easy
but counting stock giving the right
tickets
it's not easy not that i really know
because i didn't build any of it at the
same time doc ren and i were trying to
work out who the jangler was and you
know what it seems kind of obvious now
but at the time it really wasn't
it could have been any one of the
hermits messing with us and then there's
a jangler place i think the general
place is just over here
there we go it ended over here
with the jangler cookies i can't
remember what we did
it's a place and order or something and
that's it
i think that might be dangerous down
there
i don't want to find out but they ended
up with the jangler cookie here and
scott you could just tell scar made this
is absolutely beautiful well we solved
the mystery of the jungler and then we
brought out something that everyone's
been uh telling me to bring back for a
long time but i just haven't i haven't
it's hermit news
herman news was actually super fun but i
didn't really stick with it i think
that's the sort of thing that it only
really works once or twice
[Music]
and this is like our little camera
studio here where we told the the news
of the day it only really works if
there's something really insane going on
plus i'm pretty sure that the uh the the
recap wouldn't wouldn't have uh would
have been wouldn't have enjoyed that but
swiftly after hermit news happened and
just think about that for a second we
just went through a whole bunch of stuff
the 1.14 update came around and then we
needed to go to some hello
someone started a demise booby trap here
and it looks like it uh it worked the
114 update came about and we headed over
to a brand new land and i actually i
actually went through in a boat if you
remember a flying machine and i broke
through the barrier to the 114 area
second now
just give me
give it get a second just give me a
second
wait that actually worked
[Laughter]
super cool
whoa looks like there was an explosion
here there's traps being set off left
right and center
i'm actually kind of scared i need to be
more careful
and when we broke through the 114 area
we found ourselves a little village and
to be honest with you there's not a lot
left there's some of the original
buildings here but when we started this
was just a minecraft village
huh salmon ghost is gone and the story
of hermitcraft's been pretty pretty nuts
but here we are we had a lot of the
original buildings here and one of them
was my little hut you can still see it
you can still see the original build i
might have improved it slightly but
there it is
and then it all kicked off
no he didn't
he just saw that my i'm making this
slightly bigger
this this no this is beyond coincidence
he saw that the chimney was
just above his and then he decided to
make a giant antenna i see i see you
mumbo jumbo i know what you're playing
at if you remember correctly what
happened next was iskaw built his house
a little bit bigger than mine and i
couldn't i couldn't have that mumbo
built his a little taller than mine and
so i had to make mine a little taller
then iska made his a little taller
then i made mine a little taller and
then all of a sudden out of nowhere scar
comes in and he wants to build his house
above everyone else's so i build mine a
little taller and before you know it a
full-scale build-off is going on without
any preparation
and this is the result this is
definitely one of the most memorable
parts of hermitcraft for me just logging
on every day and seeing a new thing
and each one of us knew we couldn't just
go straight up to build height because
it's just not it's not that's not how
it's done you've got to build it up bit
by bit and i'm glad we did and we ended
up with a dragon we ended up with a
giant wizard plant and a castle and
whatever dabbing penguin iskall made
and then mumbo mumbo surrendered all in
one
man this is
amazing
but yet this was actually quite a long
time ago the build-off well it might
have been you know in the latter half's
but the village built up the build-off
dominated the scene
and then when it was done
we
we judged each other's buildings and
ended up with the same result
yeah i think this is definitely one of
the fondest things i i'm just i'm
enjoying this reminisce this this
journey that we've been on for the last
couple years has been absolutely amazing
but would you believe it even though
sahara had started before the build off
it didn't actually open
until after the build off so we need to
head back to sahara now we had a song we
had fireworks
and it was yeah it was actually a bit of
a disaster because it didn't work and in
fact most of the shop didn't work
everyone that shopped there actually had
a really hard time and it was super
embarrassing but look at us now look
go
[Music]
this is better than i thought it would
look
yes
look at us now we've got sahara we got
saharan now we got a functioning shop we
got a big old pile of diamonds look at
us
it was a massive success but it took a
little bit of teething and there's
actually one thing that i've um
definitely forgotten about our journey
so far some of the mini games that i
started before the head hunt even
started i think very early on we started
a game of tag now the tag kind of
petered out it's not the kind of game
that can go on forever and i think when
when scar had it it was probably time to
retire it so i don't even know if the
tag went anywhere i believe it retired
and it's it's currently retired at the
golf course enjoying its retirement
but there was if we get out of concorp
which absolutely insane i mean this is
part journey part server tour
look at concord man this is all cub
cub has done a phenomenal job i mean i
think we need to stop a little second
and just take all this in
look at this
this is part farm part factory part
build part corporate greed cub fan
look at this amazing builds and
expensive blocks look at all those
bricks and stuff
very very awesome place even if it is
concorp shakes fist but what we came
here to look at was the tag building
which is something that was actually
really frustrating if you got tagged you
had to come here you had to write your
name down you had to do a little parkour
it was a whole thing and i think
actually hermits got so annoyed with
being tagged that might have been why
they were like no i don't want to tag
anyone else just because i don't want
them to have to do this and there was
also oh wait i'm getting spammed with oh
wait the jangler cookie oh man look at
all this oh no no no okay okay okay
right we're leaving because i don't want
to risk being dead in demise
so that was going on in the background
but tag eventually
went and uh it eventually petered out
so that was going on in the background
but it eventually it had it had to go
and in fact some projects never actually
saw the light of day like all of these
studios and stuff i think they're still
pretty much unused and i don't know if
this castle ever had a story behind it
some builds you build just like my lava
mansion in the mini game district like i
don't think i'm ever gonna finish that
just because the passion for the project
is gone i've got i've got other things
that i'd rather make but anyway after we
marketed sahara
we actually started a new game because
tag wasn't enough apparently for me and
we started the hot potato game where we
passed it on to many people actually i
have no idea if the hot potatoes even
doing anything at the moment has it
does anyone know where the hot potato is
can can anyone confirm
where the hot potato is who has it
what's it doing and could you
theoretically put like you know die in
demise in it and then you know game over
for you that's
that's
that's dastardly
anyway the hot potato is somewhere and
then the mini game district was born so
now we have to go back and actually it's
actually a really good point because
traveling through the nether
was pretty much a way of life during the
114 hermitville days traveling through
here you had to do it three or four
times an hour
an hour it was it was pretty insane but
i want to also point out while we're
here just how amazing this nether hub is
look it's an identical block for block
replica
of what one for one scale of our island
with all the portals in the correct
place
and just i didn't have anything to do
with this like this was grinded out i
think mainly by false symmetry all of
this black concrete makes up the sky
remember we're in the nether it's very
easy to forget how huge this nether hub
is
it may not be the most easy thing to to
traverse but you can't deny
it's pretty impressive so we got to head
back if we want to continue our story
and we're actually fast catching up with
the present on our green story on
hermitcraft
there's also probably lots of stuff i've
forgotten as well but i mean there's
just i mean if you want to if you wanted
a recap of the entire series just just
watch the series again
at some point around this time i think i
lost my diamonds and i think we all know
who the culprit was but around this time
the mini game district had begun we
started with dig straight down which was
incredibly successful by the way and
there's even more diamonds in here i'm
gonna have to reset this at some point
look at that more diamonds oh oh oh
redstone perfect fancy
oh this is good i like it
but you have to remember there's lava at
some point in the game
so oh no
[Music]
oh no
and i totally knew before you went in
but we started the minigame district and
then they all started popping up we had
even had iscal siege of doom which um we
haven't actually played like i said some
projects they never see the light of day
but they're still part of the story
which is awesome it was around this time
that i traveled back in time and i stole
my own diamonds
it's pretty simple but if all of those
are done and i think three turns should
do it one
two
three
okay
did that work
let's go out and check
well
it definitely worked we have moved at
least
they are here so what we're gonna do is
we
are just going to return these to my
ender chest
in the future
and there's lots of things like the
overlap and one of them was area 77
the beginnings of area 77 had begun doc
and scar had started building all of
this stuff i think it started very small
yeah just with this little hanger here
and then they moved and hid my time
machine and in response i became hippie
green and we made hippy land over here
with our rvs with ren bob what ever
happened to renbob has renbob retired i
love i love rembob his van's still here
so maybe he's just chilling still but
look look at this this is this is a
problem with me and next season next
season i'm not it's too late for me now
next season i've got to be better at
organizing my stuff look at how much
junk there is and wasted shelter boxes
if i actually
bothered to put this in a sorting system
i bet i would be one of the richest
hermits there is i just leave junk look
at all this iron blocks and stuff i just
leave junk everywhere and i bet there's
even more over here yet look at this
unacceptable
and oh this this was my red barn this
was my first proper farm that i made and
it is actually really cool i might have
had a little bit of help and i
definitely followed some tutorials look
at all this
wasted it's all wasted
look at this
i made farms
they all work they all feed into each
other this is i mean it's very very
inefficient but if i was to do it again
i would know what to do better but look
at what
look at this it's actually got loads and
loads of stuff in it i'm never gonna run
out of green dye that's for sure all
bone meal i think there's plenty of bone
meal
actually i might have used a lot of it
but there's flowers galore
man
what that was successful
we had um the hippie re-education center
look we got some hip villagers over
there we
this is so cool so anyway after hippie
land we launched the rv into the air
with a giant countdown and then we
launched the rv outwards and then it
crashed
into area 77 over there at the same time
we planted flowers galore very nice
all right let's get this thing in the
air so this is the moment that everyone
has been waiting for it is time to
rebuild this giant rv
right up in the sky this is exactly what
everyone's been anticipating
everywhere and the bone meal because of
the biomes didn't actually do that much
in the rv
hit the cliff
and we had completed the distraction i
cannot believe
for a second that they removed all the
flowers honestly this is ridiculous
because we spent hours planting them all
and they removed them all
it's absolutely ridiculous what fair
play to them
i have no idea what's going on here but
fair play to them oh
oh no
oh i almost died
elytra broken i gotta be more careful
oh no
we don't have we don't have a lot of
elytra going on well area 77 happened or
we've oh we can't skip the secret tunnel
because so much time went into this the
secret tunnel was of course how we
actually made our way in with the
infiltration to area 77 the flowers was
a decoy there's even a decoy room like
cleo made this for us
it was really really awesome i'm really
enjoying going through this story by the
way and then we had a gigantic tunnel
going into aeris mt77 absolutely
fantastic now it was around this sort of
time that we started
to advertise sahara now which is where
this blimp came from and we've been here
fairly recently so i'm not going to go
inside and then idea which is um not
copyright at all uh
colors and things uh this this popped up
which is a brand new shop by corrales
excisumer and v dubs we need to be
careful we're going to break our elec
lighter again
is xp me open still because we could
definitely use this
well after sahara now
there's actually not a lot left to the
story because it was around this time
that we actually started the game of
demise i actually put a potato in sahara
at some point in here my timeline might
be a bit muddled it's been a long time
there's been a lot of things happening
it was around this time that the demise
game had officially begun and the prize
pool and that's pretty much where we are
today we then started building the
bunker and then we started dragon bros
look at this we got all of these guys
still alive somehow and then the dead
team over there it's growing wait yeah
cubs died x jevin
in fact i think this isn't even up to
date we should make an up-to-date board
of everyone who is dead or alive in the
game of demise but that is pretty much
the story
of green on hermitcraft so far
and i gotta say even though i've got my
dragon head that i can't take off i
gotta say
thank you seriously
thank you everyone it's been
um yeah i'm just i'm just really really
grateful this has been absolutely
amazing it's been what a story what a
story so far and the great thing is
we're not quite done we are not quite
done with our story yet i just thought
episode 100 would be such a good time
to sort of
just remember how far we've come on all
of this
but if we're truly gonna bring ourselves
back up to speed we gotta go
to the demise bunker speaking of which
we recently turned b dubs into a dragon
bro
and
we kind of need to tell him what's going
on so i'm gonna call iskao and tell him
to meet me at the sahara meeting room so
we can bring him up to speed on things
you summoned me here yes it's my turn
for a meeting because i remember how the
last one went i ended up with uh with
this on my head
beautiful
welcome
i've got i've got something to to show
you and it it's actually quite related
to that hold on um
you can come out now
oh what have you done
what have you done dude
[Laughter]
is that cursor binding yeah
he's a dragon bro yeah i i gotta say
scale it was easier than you would think
i just i told him to look in the
dispenser and he did and it was it was
literally as simple as that
[Laughter]
so i thought we could like show him our
little bunker and maybe like rename it
from architect to like dragon bros
because that's our whole thing now
dragon banks dragon ball dragon dragon
bunker um should we get beat ups in here
hello
he looks so gorgeous with your mouth
open action
hold on let me let me present you with a
chair
oh yeah oh there you go you got your own
oh this is this is nice you guys the
person who used to sit there never comes
to meetings yeah right
right okay is this nicer than his chair
yeah actually uh he's not good yeah his
his actually it's up there oh
yeah
we need we actually gonna we're gonna
need a dragon meeting room so what i um
did uh was i put the dragon head on uh b
dubs here and just said you're a dragon
bro now but he doesn't actually know
what that means and
also i kind of don't know what that
means i have no idea what it means other
than that it sounds cool yeah dragon
bros i think our mission statement is
anyone that's alive we should try and
make a dragon bro
oh i like that idea
that's nice yes yeah yes okay so um
i said this this last time that our
mission was to make mumbo a dragon bro
but he actually wasn't afk until today
press tab you'll see a mumbo jumbo with
a grey nail oh
yes
after we show b-dubs our rad dragon
bunker
then we're gonna go and see if we can
find mumbo this is what we do b dubs we
plot we execute we dragon bros
oh i love it that's a great motto
yeah we're gonna we're gonna need i
think we're gonna need to give b dubs
some some wings here
like it maybe it's a ceremony dragons
have wings we can't have a dragon
walking along the form isn't isn't the
definition of a dragon that they have
wings otherwise they're like a worm
isn't that but
why be a dragon if you can't fly yeah
like yeah it's like being a pirate
without without the pirate hat yeah or a
pirate without the the stump leg or a
hook
you're not a pirate i've got this reflex
i have this reflex whenever i grab wings
i grab diamond boots and and you said
that's not are you exactly are you no no
are you a dragon
or are you not no one cares about
diamond boots right right let's go to
the bunker and then let's give him some
wings
it's hard to walk through here with this
big mask on uh yeah all right so b-dubs
um we're gonna go down together okay
otherwise you're gonna die
oh
okay follow agree and immediately when
he jumps down yeah you're ready
which way are you going the water or the
other okay
don't come down here without a key card
just a
bit of public safety information
okay yeah okay i won't i won't here's
the key card by the way i could be could
be good to have
okay so come over here i've actually
made a dragon head but um
yeah
from here it looks great but when you
get like down the bottom here
you can't you can't tell what it is at
all so admire from us you're totally
you're totally sold on this dragon i
told you i'd be in on the dragon bros
yeah this is great
oh
i can fit i can fit like a redstone
entrance here dude that's what i was
hoping
hold on this is actually a really good
place
let's let's let's give let's give b dubs
his dragon wings go enter the mouth
b-dubs and become a dragon bro
yes
all right let's go again we always do
this by
yeah this isn't a new thing we i promise
we do this every day every second like
this isn't just something we made up
right now uh i'm guessing that mumbo is
at his witch farm which is um which
which is where we thought he would be
before so let's go and check there
yep
uh which means going into the nether
which is extremely dangerous at the
moment there's traps everywhere
i'll go first very careful i'll go first
good no i'll go
no i'll go
be the dragons about being brave
exactly
says you
what i have a dispenser no i have the
dragon head mumbo dragon i i got like
this is why we're a team this is why
we're dragging
stuff yeah i got the redstone stuff
you got the uh
you got the dragon let's go i mean
wouldn't you assume that there would be
a dispenser around here somewhere
that's a good point
dispenser's everywhere
oh he's not here
oh he's not oh what no
this is his afk spot
wait wait he built a new farm recently
he built an iron farm didn't he oh this
is this is him
he shouldn't in theory
he should be here
now i've done i've done a little bit of
mumbo trolling in my days uh i i know
some of his favorite afk spots i mean
this is this is target number one but
the only other space he would
realistically be is his base but
yeah maybe his slime farm or something
and he's got a few farms around his base
so he might be there
you know how dangerous it is to be
traveling to all these places with all
these traps about yeah but we're trying
to break us
we're going to go here we're going to go
there that's very dang dragon bro means
we have to be foolish we can be brave
but but foolish
maybe we just go back to sahara and just
kind of relax
in the in the base
or maybe we don't
he sometimes afk is around here maybe
his farm i don't actually know where his
uh normal afk spot is because none of
this is actually safe mumbo's base is
just not safe at all oh he has one over
here by his villager breeder and he's
not here
he's not here he's not here but no we've
got the creeper farm uh oh what about
the group no
no it's not here hold on let me take a
good look underground
this man this man is the man with the
molestation of k sports he has a lot of
memories
don't worry i know where all of them are
i i have captured them in my time
uh
well we've actually checked most of them
there's a new one but he doesn't really
go there maybe yeah creeper farm one
where's his demise bunker that's the one
i want to check next i don't actually
know where it is i know how to get there
from the the
bunker he made a stupidly long tunnel
oh there it is there it is oh my
goodness i couldn't load it in there it
is i know it's around here somewhere
yes but be quiet
is he even hit is he even here
i have no idea maybe we should talk a
little quieter no wait hold on before we
go i mean i i did just big up being a
big brave dragon but um mumbo's base or
mumbo's demise bunker is actually
protected by stuff
yes okay
we'll be careful then
okay okay all right
okay
but theoretically he shouldn't he
shouldn't be attacking us anyway because
we're we're all watching
well i mean he doesn't know that
i don't see his name
he might not be here
oh
my goodness sake
don't pull him
hold on
be dumbs get up why stand watch stand
here by the ladders okay stand there by
them yeah stand there i'm not wearing
diamond do i just stand there just time
for a second i'll be brave i'm a brave
dragon
i can do it go ahead
stop it let's go
oh i thought he was gonna die
yes you're one of us now one one dragon
star there you go
yeah okay thank you i can't breathe i'm
i'm like oh
oh man
i thought it could be funny
let's go
we're the dumbest dragons there ever
were
um
i don't know how far up this lava goes
let's just take the long way and by long
way i mean the longest way
it doesn't get much longer than this
i'll be honest with you dudes we're
we're in for a uh not a treat
the opposite of a treat is what we're in
for
i hope you
guys
no no it's definitely not trapped i just
it feels like one
chilling
come i'm sorry
hey we're back at the dragon yeah
worship land all right let's keep
looking
that was really nice of mumbo to make
that tunnel
i think we're gonna have to take away
his dragon head
unless he's just somewhere random we
might have missed him
i mean who built an iron farm with 4 000
iron per hour without afking at it come
on now that got to be why he's afk we've
got we must have missed him at some
point
in my last video he must know that we
are after him
therefore he has switched his afk spot
in the perimeter
i don't think mumbo thinks that way
i think he just
thinks that way he is
we're about to take that away
yes right if he's not up up there
he must be somewhere around his new iron
farm oh dude
he's literally right here in this giant
iron box yeah
and my goodness okay where is this this
is a show off for how much iron he's
earning now or oh that's a great brand
no no no no i found it i found it i
found it there's a there's a combination
there's a combination lock
there's a combination oh do you know the
combination uh no
ah all of these lava sounds are making
me really panicky dude
i don't think these are these look like
this
these don't do anything where's beat ups
i i i i don't know what the iron box is
dragon ever if these are if these are
indicating what the code is i could
guess that it would be
i'm gonna try something
oh no that that wouldn't work because
there are no four buttons in there
wait wait wait for beat up beat ups beat
ups we're over here you see us down here
down you were going the right way and
then you weren't i was okay no no now
you're going wrong
now you're going the right way see us
hello it feels good
didn't you or didn't your dragon head
come with the latest gps mine did no
actually i didn't get that version
lucky for you i am a combination master
all you have to do is stick your ear
real close okay stick your ear real
close now watch this watch it stand back
though stand back i can't be
bothered all right i don't know what it
is i assume it opens the door
and there we go and in two seconds just
wait
you hear that
okay that didn't work especially that i
haven't done it
you just gotta think like mumbo jumbo
what would he do for a combination lock
one
one huh
i heard something
no no not yet no
do we just try every combination
one two three four
[Laughter]
you did it
look at
did him leave his combination one two
three four and he seriously takes time
to build this thing
and he left it one two three
this this is the prop weak passwords
that's the problem if your password is
one two three four you are you are
susceptible um he's made this so easy
oh look at him bless him look at this
gorgeous man
i think we should let b-dubs do the
honors
okay yeah yeah i'll put i'll put the
mumbo dragon i head on in in the
dispenser for you and then
you just gotta activate it
mumbo jumbo we bless you with the head
of the dragon the head of the dragon
dragon
look at us one of us
yeah why is he got so many beds you know
i'm taking one of these beds
yeah me too i need i need one of these
beds that's your first donation as a
dragon bro mumbo
he's gonna be i'm pretty sure mumbo has
no idea what what dragon bros are i mean
we didn't know until we started this
thing so he's gonna be so confused
i wonder i wonder how long it takes for
him to notice it
how long does it notice how long does it
take that he can't play through the
episode i reckon eric into that half
yeah i mean there are no mirrors in
minecraft so no no he always does his
intro face on though so he's gonna
notice
wait let me try it
hello everybody this is bamboo and
welcome back to another episode of the
hermitcraft server this is episode 500
yeah i don't know if you would notice
that dude
you think even if he's doing his intro
he's not going to notice
maybe not maybe not
dragon bro mission accomplished
we did it
achievement get back back to the bunker
wait we should totally close this up
back to the bunker
hold on hold on hold on hold on
hold on hold on
one last thing
he comes back he opens his door with his
redstone
yes
and the door doesn't fully open
oh classic
back to the bunker now
and we got mumbo pretty good i forgot to
add the pickles to patrick's house so
we're going to do that now because it
needs to be all light down here
but what an episode it has been episode
what an episode it has been a bit of a
recap but i think it's kind of important
to
remember
what we've been through to get here so
far
and iskales actually told me that he's
made some improvements already to the
dragon bunker we have got mumbai did you
know what mumbo is still afk it's been
like a full 24 hours since we got him
and he's still afk unbelievable that man
doesn't stop so next episode we're
definitely going to have to get our
hands
on some more we're gonna have to get our
hands on some more dragon heads
so he told me he's done something here
but aha
do we just
you'll be you got to be careful of any
pressure plate these days
oh my goodness
oh my goodness this is awesome
the dragon bro bunker is here and we got
space for more
this is so cool mumbo's here i'm here
isgal's here and we go uh he's even
already done it enemies of the bros rip
rest in peace the demise so there's a
team of eight that's a pretty formidable
team actually so we've gotta we've gotta
be really really careful here so next
episode we're gonna have to get the
dragon bros together work out what our
what what is our plan
i think our plan is to just be bros and
to get as many people with dragon heads
as possible
but since this is episode 100 i do
actually want to do something a little
special to finish this episode off
because
it's it you know it's it's episode 100
and i think it should be a little longer
i think it should be a little emotional
so there's actually something i've been
wanting to do for a really long time to
the base i've always considered my
minecraft base my hermitcraft base here
i've considered it finished i've
considered it finished for a really long
time which is why i haven't had a lot of
building to do other than the sahara
area here i haven't really had a lot to
do with it and i'm ignoring the um
interior of this design just because
there's really not much point they would
just be doing the interior for the
interior's sake
but there's actually something i would
really really like to add to this build
just to make it that little bit bigger
that little bit more grand
and then i think i can be absolutely 100
sure that it's
finished and what i want to do is just a
little addition similar to these
but one two three four
around the outside of it and then we'll
call this base 100 finished on episode
100 of hermitcraft
[Music]
you